(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T05:58:20.146617",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
“Let’s get it going,” さあ 始めよう…
“Let’s get it going,” come on, let’s begin…
僕らの名の下に
so, in our own name
bring it, bring it on
can't stop! ! !
we can’t stop! ! !
目障りな騒音には get out
all the pandemonium is an eyesore, so get out
挑発するように舌出して bye now
stick your tongue out to provoke them, say bye now
不屈不撓 唯々昇るさ
we’re indomitable, we’ll only ascend more
余暇見出せるの？ 出せない you see
can you look away? no, you can’t, so you’ll see
risk伴った愉快さが don't stop
risk tags along with the fun, hey don’t stop
play out 朽ちてゆけお前が
play out, or you’ll be forgotten in time
逆巻く熱を帯びて全身全霊 checkmate
we carry our surging passions in our body and soul, checkmate
意思表示する叫びの金環際 容赦しない condition
we call out our declaration of intent that we won’t go easy under any condition
僕ら色のscenarioは never end…
tinged in our color, this scenario will never end…
ahhh! !
ahhh!!
i will win against!
i will win against—!
運命は僕らさ 魂を魂で穿って
destiny is ours! strike souls against souls
i know (you know?) you know? (i know)
“we get to the top” (3, 2, 1, jump!)
“we get to the top” — 3, 2, 1, jump!
i will win against!
i will win against—!
前人未踏の地へ 絶対的な存在へと
to go to an undiscovered land, to become an absolute existence
i know (you know?) you know? (i know)
a declaration of ✕✕✕ 此処に…
a declaration of ✕✕✕, here… listen!
聴け！
listen!
例え声を枯らしても don't care
even if your voice withers away, just don’t care
喉の奥から求めて sing it
call it back from the depths of your throat, and sing it
不承不承生るのはやめろよ
stop living your life so reluctantly
淫らに鳴る戯言 go away
all that annoying nonsense needs to go away
鼓膜揺るがせ脊髄で feeling
we’ll rattle your ear drums and your spinal cord with this feeling
play out 後は見下ろすだけ
play out, then just look down on it all
激情の渦が示す未来の姿 showing up
this vortex of fury represents how the future will be showing up
支配するeye contact 世界中を切っ盛り裂いてゆけ
this dominating eye contact will tear the world to shreds
僕ら色のmemoryは never die…
tinged in our color, this memory will never die…
ahhh! !
ahhh!!
i will win against!
i will win against—!
運命が僕らさ 魂を魂で掴んで
destiny is ours! seize souls with souls
i know (you know?) you know? (i know)
“we get to the top” (3, 2, 1, jump!)
“we get to the top” — 3, 2, 1, jump!
i will never die
夢中で走った この道の途中で
Running through a daze, midway down this road,
何度も何度も 躓いて 転んで
Stumbling and falling over and over again,
描いた 未来が 見えなくなったって 諦めたく 無かった
Even when the future I pictured became invisible, I didn't want to give up.
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
その先へ行けるならば
If we can go beyond that point.
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
今巡る音に乗せて
Riding on the revolving sound right now.
i will never die
独りで悩んで見出した活路も
Even the path I found while worrying alone,
忘れてたものを取り戻した夜も
And the night I regained what I had forgotten,
どんなときだって
No matter what the time was,
君は囁いてくれた
You whispered to me,
僕の手を引きながら
While pulling my hand along.
変わっていく時代の中で輝いてる
Shining amidst the changing times,
君ともう少し未来へ進むために
To move a little further into the future with you,
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
その先へ行けるならば
If we can go beyond that point.
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
今巡る音に乗せて
Riding on the revolving sound right now.
i will never die
変わっていく時代の中で輝いてる
Shining amidst the changing times,
君ともう少し未来へ進むために
To move a little further into the future with you,
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
その先へ行けるならば
If we can go beyond that point.
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
今巡る音に乗せて
Riding on the revolving sound right now.
絶対的な救いへと
Toward absolute salvation,
i will never die , i will never end
I will never die, I will never end,
i will never die
今巡る音に乗せて
Riding on the revolving sound right now,
i will never die
天球、彗星は夜を跨いで 作詞・作曲：キタニタツヤ
[Title: Tenkyuu, Suisei wa Yoru o Matai de / Lyrics & Music: Tatsuya Kitani]
明かりがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on.
天を彩った繻子が綺麗だ
The satin adorning the heavens is beautiful.
僕の吐いた白い息のように、消してしまえたらな
If I could erase it like my white breath...
押し殺して深く沈んだ
Suppressing it, sinking deep down,
泣き声さえ、聴こえているから
Even the crying voice can be heard.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
Both the anxiety and pain that pierced you,
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Painted over in my blue color.
全部涙になって
Everything turned into tears,
星の海を流れていった
Flowing away into the sea of stars.
果てしない闇の中に
Deep within the endless darkness,
そっと青を添えたら、ほら
If I gently add blue to it, look—
彗星が僕の頭上を飛んだ
A comet flew right above my head,
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
Dyeing the empty night sky.
深く寝静まった街の中へ
Into the deeply slumbering town,
降り注ぐのは誰の悲しみだろう
Whose sorrow is it that pours down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
A comet flew again, drawing an arc,
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
Clearing away the hazy thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't say, "We'll meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はまだ
In the town after the stars fell, I am still...
黒くくすんだランデブーの空を
The darkly tarnished sky of our rendezvous,
彗星が彩るように
As if adorned by a comet.
君を刺した不安も苦痛も
Both the anxiety and pain that pierced you,
僕の青色で塗り潰して
Painted over in my blue color.
君の涙をそっと、星の海に流し込むんだ
Gently pouring your tears into the sea of stars,
大きくなったその光が、誰かをまた救うから
That grown light will save someone once again.
彗星が遠くへ旅のなら
If the comet travels far away,
この空を全部君にあげる
I will give this entire sky to you.
灯りがひとつ灯った 灯った
A single light flickered on, flickered on.
言葉の尾を引いて
Dragging the tail of words,
降り注ぐのは 誰の悲しみだろう
whose sorrow is it that pours down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The star flew again, drawing an arc,
街の視線を奪い去るように
as if stealing away the gaze of the city.
君とまた会えるなら 僕はそうだ
If I can meet you again, that's right,
星の名前をひとつ 受け止めよう
I will accept one name of a star.
悲しみが溢れそうになること
When sadness is about to overflow,
天球で離れ離れでも
even if we are separated across the celestial sphere,
僕らは繋がってるから
we are connected after all.
彗星が突然頭上を飛んだ
A comet suddenly flew overhead,
誰もいない夜の空を染めた
dyeing the empty night sky.
深く沈まった街の中へ
Deep into the sunken city,
降り注ぐのは 誰の悲しみだろう
whose sorrow is it that pours down?
星はまた弧を描いて飛んだ
The star flew again, drawing an arc,
もやのかかった思考を晴らして
clearing away the hazy thoughts.
「いつかまた会える」なんて言えなかった
I couldn't even say "We can meet again someday."
星が降ったあとの街、僕はもうずっと
In the town after the stars fell, I have forever
君の行方を捜してた
been searching for where you went.
ああ、皆さん！
Ah, everyone!
ああ、見えますか！
Ah, can you see me?
見えてるよ、みんなのコメントも。
I can see everyone's comments too.
はい、ということで始まりました、星街すいせい50万人記念ライブ！
Yes, so it has started, Hoshimachi Suisei's 500k commemorative live!
はい、ということでいつもの挨拶からやっていきたいと思います。
Yes, so I'd like to start with my usual greeting.
彗星の如く現れた星の原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
The rough diamond appearing like a comet, VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
せーの、Switch On!
Ready, Switch On!
今日は、今日だよ、今日！
Today is the day, today!
今日は、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
2曲だけですでに疲れ切ってしまった。
I'm already exhausted just from two songs.
はい、ということで1曲目はレーザーシレンの
Yes, so the first song was Laser Siren's...
1曲目は、私星街すいせいの「天球、彗星は夜を跨いで」でした！
The first song was my, Hoshimachi Suisei's, "Tenkyuu, Suisei wa Yoru o Mataide"!
どうだったかな？どうだったかな皆さん？
How was it? How was it, everyone?
いや、本当に、あのリハをですね、何度もやっていたんですけども、なんか、や、やっと本番というか
Man, truly, we did rehearsals so many times, but finally the real thing...
本番が来てしまったという感じが、ちょっと緊張がヤバくて。
it felt like the real thing had arrived, and my nervousness was crazy.
あ、もうこれもしやして、本当の本番なのかな？みたいな、なんか本当にちょっと緊張が声に表れていたかもしれないですが、
Maybe my nervousness showed in my voice,
あの、カッコよく歌えたらいいなと思っておりまして。
but I was hoping I could sing it coolly.
てことで、今回はですね、50万人、チャンネル登録者数50万人を記念して、このライブを開催させていただきました！
So, this time, we held this live to commemorate 500,000 subscribers!
50万人突破ありがとうございます！本当にありがとう！
Thank you for reaching 500k! Thank you so much!
ありがとうみんな！ありがとうみんな！
Thank you everyone! Thank you everyone!
はい、最高だったよ、ありがとう！見えております、コメントが。
Yes, it was great, thank you! I can see your comments.
はい、えーそしてですね、あの星街すいせい
Yes, and also, Hoshimachi Suisei
50万人記念ライブというタグがありまして、
has a 500k commemorative live hashtag,
ちょっと、今出ますかね？あれ、今出てる？ここら辺にきっと
will it appear now? Huh, is it showing? It should be
出て、あ、で、え？出ない？
showing around here, ah, bu-, huh? Not showing?
なんか、あの、以前は出ると聞いていたんですけど、なんか今日出ないらしくて！
I heard it would appear before, but somehow it seems it's not showing today!
え、すいません、あのタイトルのほ、ここ、ここ、ここ、タイトルのほうに
Um, sorry, in the title, here, here, here, in the title area,
あの星街すいせい、あ、50万人記念ライブというあのハッシュタグがありますので、
there is the Hoshimachi Suisei 500k commemorative live hashtag,
こちら、こちらのツイートして、ぜひツイートしてください！
so please tweet this, please be sure to tweet!
出ないんかい！そう、出ないんかい！
It's not showing?! Right, it's not showing?!
本当にすいませんって今言われました。
Someone just told me "I'm really sorry."
はい、ということで、えっと実を言うと
Yes, so, actually,
今日、あの特別な回として、すごくいろんなことをあの組み立てておりまして、
today, as a special occasion, I've put together a lot of things,
まずスペシャルのこと、第1、第1、第1として、ゲストが来てくれます！
and first as special part 1, a guest is coming!
次の歌はゲストと一緒に歌いますよ！
We'll sing the next song together with the guest!
とっくの一瞬の あいつとの 天命を塗り替えた
In an instant long ago, I rewrote the destiny I shared with him.
カンカンと響いた あいつの 足音を
The sound of his footsteps echoing with a metallic clanging—
目線は俯いていて どんてんはうねっていて
With downcast eyes, beneath a surging, gloomy sky,
キッキッキッと睨んだまま 素足は艶やかに
Glaring with a clicking sound, my bare feet gleam gracefully.
重ねた天の平に見えた
Seen on the palm of the piled-up heavens,
祝福という名の 赤い 魂
A red soul named blessing.
来世 浄土 痺れを利かせて
In the next life, the Pure Land, letting numbness take over,
彷徨う 心は 叫び出す
My wandering heart begins to cry out.
瞳の奥の 誓いの証明
Deep within my eyes, the proof of an oath—
燃やせ 深く 深く
Burn it, deeper and deeper,
闇に咲いた 太陽
The sun blooming in the darkness!
とっくの一瞬の 宵闇と 呪われたことのは
In an instant long ago, twilight and cursed words—
タンタンと相槌打てば 笑顔は消えてく ああ
If I nod along mechanically, my smile fades away, ah.
チチチと舌打ちした 吐息は誰のせい？
Clicking my tongue, whose fault is this sigh?
今宵の光り 遮らせた 青白い魂
The pale soul that blocked tonight's light—
来世も 夢も 一悪の定め
Next life, dreams, the destiny of a single villain—
難民二人とも 怪我させない
Neither of us refugees will get hurt.
揺るがぬ 月の 光の中で 何を 誰を 救うの？
Within the unwavering moonlight, what and whom are we saving?
悪夢を呑んだ 梟の鳴き声
The hoot of an owl that swallowed a nightmare,
一つずつ 途絶えゆく 花びら
Petals fading away one by one.
眩い閃光が 唯一の道を照らした
Ah, a dazzling flash of light illuminated the only path.
来世も 夢も 一悪の定め 難民二人とも 怪我させない
Next life, dreams, the destiny of a single villain, neither of us refugees will get hurt.
揺るがぬ 月の 光の中で 誰を 想うの？
Within the unwavering moonlight, who are you thinking of?
来世も 夢も 一悪の定め
Next life, dreams, the destiny of a single villain—
彷徨う 心は 叫び出す
My wandering heart begins to cry out.
瞳の奥の 誓いの証明
Deep within my eyes, the proof of an oath—
燃やせ 燃やせ
Burn it, burn it,
闇に咲いた 太陽
The sun blooming in the darkness!
don't touch me !
Don't touch me!
喰らいついてこれるか この精神愛
Can you keep up with this platonic love?
体はいつも正直なんだよ
My body is always honest, you know
目で見るリアルが全てじゃない
The reality you see with your eyes isn't everything
君だけに sick ! for you
Just for you, sick ! for you
触れたい欲望 vs 触れない愛情
Desire to touch vs Affection unable to touch
その距離 アバウト 十ミリメートル !
That distance is about ten millimeters !
そんな 薄い 薄い 膜 を 隔て て
Separated by such a thin, thin membrane
これ が 愛 だ と 叫ん で いる の さ
Crying out that this is love
（ no way ! ）
( no way ! )
君 は 狼 なん です
You are a wolf
（ so what ! ）
( so what ! )
i ’ m not akazukin
I'm not Little Red Riding Hood
（ shake me ! ） 危険 地帯 に 突入
( shake me ! ) Rush into the danger zone
甘く なく て も 溶け て いく の さ
Even if it's not sweet, it's melting away
crush on you baby !
platonic girl platonic girl
endless love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
endless love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
触れ ない で 抱きあっ て
Don't touch me, embrace each other
tenderness love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
tenderness love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
突き刺す give me more
Piercing give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
ドキドキ し て 致死 量
Pounding heart to a lethal dose
間接 kiss ! ありえない i love you
Indirect kiss ! No way i love you
（ but don’t touch me ! ）
( but don't touch me ! )
そこ から 先 は 立入禁止
Beyond that point is restricted area
甘い 果実 に 手 を 触れ たい の だ
Want to touch the sweet fruit
そこ で いい 子 に おすわり なさい
Sit down like a good boy there
ご褒美 に wink ! give me
A wink as a reward ! give me
開け たい 衝動 禁断症状
Impulse to open, withdrawal symptoms
その距離 アバウト 一ミリメートル !
That distance is about one millimeter !
そんな 切ない 切ない きわどい 関係
Such a painful, painful, risky relationship
パンドラの箱 詰まっているのは
What is packed in Pandora's box is
（ no way ! ）
( no way ! )
君 の 知ら ない 偶像
An idol you don't know
（ so what ! ）
( so what ! )
hah … god only knows …
（ shake me ! ） 狂い たい なら どうぞ
( shake me ! ) If you want to go mad, go ahead
希望 の 先 に 残っ た もの は
What remains beyond hope is
take back my love !
platonic girl platonic girl
endless love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
endless love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
しらけ ない で 朝 まで
Don't be a killjoy until morning
tenderness love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
tenderness love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
だから be quiet
So be quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
見つめ 合っ て いる だけ
Just staring at each other
不完全さ それ以上 求め ない で
Imperfection, don't ask for any more than that
stop !
sit down !
（ stop ! stop ! ）
( stop ! stop ! )
（ sit down ! ）
( sit down ! )
（ stop ! stop ! ）
( stop ! stop ! )
（ sit down ! ）
( sit down ! )
no way ! 君 は 狼 な ん です
no way ! You are a wolf
so what ! i ’ m not akazukin
so what ! I'm not Little Red Riding Hood
shake me ! 危険 地帯 に 突入
shake me ! Rush into the danger zone
甘く なく て も 溶け て いく の さ
Even if it's not sweet, it's melting away
one more time are you readyyyy ! !
platonic girl platonic girl
endless love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
endless love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
触れ ない で 抱きあっ て
Don't touch me, embrace each other
tenderness love （ uh uh uh uh uh ）
tenderness love ( uh uh uh uh uh )
突き刺す give me more
Piercing give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
ドキドキ し て 致死 量
Pounding heart to a lethal dose
だから be quiet
So be quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
見つめ 合っ て いる だけ ？ ？
Just staring at each other ? ?
そう それ が platonic ! platonic ! （ platonic ？ ）
Yes, that's platonic ! platonic ! ( platonic ? )
二人 の 愛 の パラダイス
The paradise of our love
間接 kiss ! ありえない i love you
Indirect kiss ! No way i love you
but don’t touch me !
but don't touch me !
sit down !
stop !
（ no way ! ）
( no way ! )
君 は 狼 なん です
You are a wolf
（ so what ! ）
( so what ! )
i ’ m not akazukin
I'm not Little Red Riding Hood
（ shake me ! ） 危険 地帯 に 突入
( shake me ! ) Rush into the danger zone
甘く なく て も 溶け て いく の さ
Even if it's not sweet, it's melting away
one more time are you readyyyy ! !
platonic girl platonic girl
endless love
触れ ない で 抱きあっ て
Don't touch me, embrace each other
tenderness love
突き刺す give me more
Piercing give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
give me more
（ give me more ）
( give me more )
ドキドキ し て 致死 量
Pounding heart to a lethal dose
だから be quiet
So be quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
quiet
（ quiet ）
( quiet )
見つめ 合っ て いる だけ
Just staring at each other
それが platonic ! platonic !
That's platonic ! platonic !
二人 の 愛 の パラダイス
The paradise of our love
間接 kiss ! ありえない i love you
Indirect kiss ! No way i love you
but don’t touch me !
but don't touch me !
有罪でいいんです
It's fine if I'm guilty,
トキメキ胸打ちは
with this fluttering heartbeat.
偶然なのです
It's just a coincidence,
アイドルなのですから
because I'm an idol!
好きになっちゃえば
Once you fall in love with me,
抗えない
you won't be able to resist.
乙女の権利ね
It's a maiden's privilege,
素敵でしょ
isn't it wonderful?
恋愛禁止 まだ早すぎね
"No dating" is still way too early!
有り？無し？どっち？
Yes? No? Which is it?
恋する女の子のハートって純情なのでしょうか？
Is a girl in love's heart really that pure?
トライアングル！ 純情な気持ちに
Triangle! To pure feelings,
嘘はついちゃダメ
telling lies is forbidden!
恋愛ハンター 超スピードで
Dating hunter, at super speed,
ルール追い越したの
I sped right past the rules!
その耳をもたない気なら 説得は無駄ね
If you won't listen, trying to reason with me is useless.
大好きなんだもん
Because I love you so much!
無罪じゃなくちゃね
It has to be innocent,
恋は自由でしょ
love is free, right?
有罪で決まり
Guilty it is!
情状酌量の余地なし
There's no room for leniency.
これって結構
This is quite
大問題
a big problem!
思いやり正直 素晴らしいわ
Consideration and honesty are wonderful.
キミゴトは絶対 本物なのよね
Your feelings are definitely real, right?
有り？無し？どっち？トライアングル！
Yes? No? Which is it? Triangle!
恋するとね みんな周りが 見えなくなるんで
When you fall in love, you lose sight of everything around you!
どんな危険だって 進んでいて なぜ落ちるのでしょう?
Why do we march into danger without hesitation?
恋愛ハンター ノーブストップで ぐっと決めちゃったの
Dating hunter, non-stop, I've made up my mind!
やっちゃっても 絶対ごめんね だからね免罪符
Even if I mess up, forgive me! That's my bill of indulgence.
心ゆれてる
My heart is swaying.
あり？手習いの人には根拠がありません！
"Is that so? There's no basis for a novice!"
あり？警察官の主張は課題がありません！
"Really? The police officer's claim has no issues!"
ねえ、どっちが正しいの？
"Hey, which one is right?"
愛しいの恋の悩みは 心で深秘です
The worries of love are a mystery of the heart.
天使と悪魔の主張 裁判は踊る
Angels and demons argue as the trial dances on.
恋する女の子のハートって純情なのでしょうか？
Is a girl in love's heart really that pure?
トライアングル！ 純情な気持ちに 嘘はついちゃダメ
Triangle! To pure feelings, telling lies is forbidden!
恋愛ハンター 超スピードで 追い越したの
Dating hunter, at super speed, I sped right past!
その耳をもたない気なら 説得は無駄ね
If you won't listen, trying to reason with me is useless.
まだ消し時計の 傾くから ギロチン！
The clock's hands tilt... guillotine!
遠い遠いそこから見るの罪ね
Viewing from far away is a sin.
はーい！
Yay!
やばーい！
Amazing!
全員疲れてる！
Everyone's exhausted!
やばい！やばい！ほんとにがんばった！
So crazy! We really did our best!
はい、ということで、ゲストはかなたと…
Yes, so our guests are Kanata and...
あ、いえーい！お疲れ様です！
Ah, yay! Good job!
凄く考えて...
I thought about it so much...
すごい考えて、あ、ね、と、あとはね
Ah, right, and, also
あ、そう、ね、もうね
Ah, right, right, also
で、と、あと一緒に、本当に最後の最後までダンスを、ダンス...
And dancing together until the very, very end...
ダンスね
Dancing
そう、あ、ここはね、こうやって、こうやって、こうだよみたいな
Yeah. Ah, here, it's like, like this, like that.
そうね、そうだね
That's right, yeah.
運動量じゃなくてさ、すいちゃんのね、すごい切れのある...
It's not about stamina, Suisei's got such sharp...
ね、で、めっちゃ最後まで教えてもらったから
Right, and she taught me right until the very end.
ギリギリまで
Right up until the end.
ギリギリまでね、やってました。はい、どうだったかな？
We kept at it till the very end. Yes, how was it?
ダンスまでねちょっと頑張ってみましたけれども
We tried our best even with the dancing, but
あ、でも、トワ様もダンスすごかったって！
Ah, but they said Towa's dancing was amazing too!
え、よかったー！
Oh, I'm so glad!
それと一応、ありがとうございます！おめでとう！
And for that, thank you! Congratulations!
おめでとう、本当にすいちゃん、ありがとうございます！
Congratulations, thank you so much, Suisei!
ありがとうございます！だもんだもんだも！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you!
はい、ということで、二人を、お呼びいたしましたけれども
Yes, so, we invited the two of them here, but
はい、実は、うん？だな
Yes, actually, huh? Is that so?
ゲストか。おー！
A guest? Oh!
ということで、この後もお楽しみに！
So look forward to after this too!
イェーイ！ご安全に！
Yay! Stay safe!
ではでは、次の曲、行ってまいりましょう！
Well then, let's go to the next song!
はい！
Yes!
強く慣れる理由を知った
I got to know the reason I could get strong.
僕を連れて進め
Take me with you and advance.
泥だらけの走馬灯に酔う
Intoxicated by the muddy lantern light,
進め
Advance!
こわばる心震える手は
My heart is frozen, my trembling hands
掴みたいものがある
Have something they want to grasp.
それだけさ
That's all.
夜の匂いに空睨んでも
Even if I stare into the sky scented with night,
変わっていけるのは自分自身だけ
The only thing I can change is myself.
それだけさ
That's all.
強く慣れる理由を知った
I got to know the reason I could get strong.
僕を連れて進め
Take me with you and advance.
どうしたって!消せない夢も
No matter what the unforgettable dreams
止まれない今も
And the unstoppable now,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I'm able to get strong for someone,
ありがとう悲しみよ
Thank you, oh sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて
Overwhelmed by the world,
負ける意味を知った
I got to know what it means to lose.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ!
Oh crimson lotus, bloom!
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny!
イナビカリの雑音が耳を刺す
The thunderous boom pierced my ears.
戸惑う心優しいだけじゃ
My heart is at a loss, just being kind,
守れないものがある
There are things I cannot protect.
わかってるけど
I know that, but
水面下で絡まる善悪
Under the water surface, good and evil are entangled,
透けて見える偽善に天罰
Divine punishment to the obvious hypocrisy.
逸材の花より 挑戦し続け咲いた一輪が美しい
The flower who kept on trying to bloom is more beautiful,
乱暴に敷き詰められた トゲだらけの道も
The road that's filled with dangerous thorns, too,
本気の僕だけに現れるから
Will only reveal itself when I'm resolute,
乗り越えてみせるよ
I will overcome it!
簡単にかたづけられた 守れなかった夢も
The easily discarded dreams, too, that I couldn't protect,
紅蓮的心臓に根を宿して
Settle the roots inside the crimson's heart,
この地に宿っている
It dwells in this blood.
人知れず 儚い散りゆく結末
The secret fleeting end that is falling apart,
無情に破れた 悲鳴の風吹く
The wind of the ruthlessly torn scream blows.
誰かの笑う影
A person's laughter,
誰かの泣き声
A person's cry,
誰もが幸せを願っている
Everyone wishes for happiness.
どうしたって!消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what the unforgettable dreams and the unstoppable now,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I'm able to get strong for someone,
ありがとう悲しみよ
Thank you, oh sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて
Overwhelmed by the world,
負ける意味を知った
I got to know what it means to lose.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ!
Oh crimson lotus, bloom!
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny!
散りゆく結末の
The ending that scatters away,
無情に破れた
Torn away ruthlessly,
秘密の風吹く
The secret wind blows.
どうしたって!消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what the unforgettable dreams and the unstoppable now,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I'm able to get strong for someone,
ありがとう悲しみよ
Thank you, oh sadness.
世界に打ちのめされて 負ける意味を知った
Overwhelmed by the world, I got to know what it means to lose.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ! 運命を照らして
Oh crimson lotus, bloom! Illuminate my destiny!
世界に打ちのめされて 負ける意味を知った
Overwhelmed by the world, I got to know what it means to lose.
紅蓮の華よ咲き誇れ! 運命を照らして
Oh crimson lotus, bloom! Illuminate my destiny!
運命を照らして
Illuminate my destiny!
きっと一人じゃない 夢の中へ行く
You're not alone, heading into a dream...
迷いながら Ready?
Wandering, ready?
GO!
やっとね 気づいたんだ
I finally realized
あなたの中の 消えない光
the unvanishing light within you.
That's light!
どこへ行ってもそれは 希望という名の
Wherever you go, it's hope's
羽だから Fly high!
wings, so fly high!
強さを求めたなら 今すぐ受け入れてみよう
If you seek strength, embrace it right now.
My heart 迷いがないことじゃ 夢は遠ざかるから
My heart—without hesitation, dreams drift away,
さあ 変わろう 新しくなれ
come on, change and become new!
光を破って 進めるね できるよ
Breaking the light, you can move forward, you can!
できるよ 次の場所へ Take off!
You can, to the next place, take off!
もっと踊りたい もっと踊りたい 真っ赤な夜空
I want to dance more, dance more in the crimson night sky!
止まらないよ Dance, spin, believe again
Unstoppable, dance, spin, believe again
空手を抱きしめながら Believe again
embracing the empty hands, believe again!
また始まるんだ Believe, believe again
It's starting again, believe, believe again!
その手を抱きしめながら Feel it
Embracing those hands, feel it!
Believe, believe again, again
また始まるんだ Don't mind, don't stop!
It's starting again, don't mind, don't stop!
諦めたって言わなくって きっと伝わるよ
Don't say you gave up, it will definitely get through!
何度でも熱くなれる 自由になれ
You can get passionate anytime, be free!
Believe, believe again, again
また始まるんだ
It's starting again!
冒険は終わらない Let's go!
The adventure never ends, let's go!
止まった楽しい場所も 終わりじゃないからね
Even a fun place that stopped isn't the end, so—
そろそろ出発 Time over!
it's almost time to depart, time over!
遅れていっても 胸に暖かい思い出が眠る My life
Even if we're late, warm memories sleep in our hearts, my life.
重くて飛べなくたって 心拭い続けて軽やかに
Even if it's too heavy to fly, keep wiping your heart to stay light.
Set out! 変化を受け入れよう
Set out! Let's embrace change.
変化を受け入れよう 夢も進化の時だった
Embrace change, for dreams are also evolving.
分かち合ってきたね 迷いを深んだ
We've shared so much, deepening our hesitations,
そして思いのままに 進めてきるね できるよ
and just as we felt, we can move forward, you can!
次の場所へ 今日も踊って 今日も踊って
To the next place! Dance today too, dance today too!
Let's dance, let's dance!
止まらないよ Dance, spin, believe again, again!
Unstoppable, dance, spin, believe again, again!
きっとひとりじゃない 夢の中へ Go!!
You're not alone, into the dream, Go!
迷いながら Ready? Go!
Hesitating, Ready? Go!
やっとね 気づいたみたい? あなたの中の消えない光
Did you finally realize? The unquenchable light inside you.
That’s right!
That's right!
どこへ行っても それは希望という名の羽だから
No matter where you go, those are wings called hope.
fly high
強さを求めたら
If you seek strength,
弱さも受け入れてみようよ
try accepting your weaknesses as well.
My fault!
余裕がない心じゃ 夢は遠ざかるのかも
Without room in your heart, dreams drift further away.
さあ、生まれ変わろう!
Now, let's be reborn!
新しくれ 古い殻を破って進め
Become new, break your old shell and move forward.
できるね できるよ 次の場所へ dash!
You can do it, dash to the next place!
もっと踊りたい
I want to dance more,
I want to dance more.
let's dance
yeah!
dance
止まらないよ dance!!
Won't stop dancing!
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
すべてを抱きしめながら
Holding everything in our arms,
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
また始まるんだ
It's starting over again.
shout my song!
本気だって言わなくってきっと伝わるよ
Even without saying we mean it, it's bound to get across.
何度でも熱くなれ 自由になれ
Be passionate anytime, be free.
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
また始まるんだ
It's starting over again.
( yeah )
yeah
yeah!!
( yeah )
yeah
そう冒険は終わらないよ let's go
Yes, the adventure never ends, let's go.
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
believe
( believe )
again
止まるなよ止まるなよ止まるなよ止まらないよ
Stop, stop, stop, won't stop!
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
すべてを抱きしめながら
While embracing everything in our arms,
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
また始まるんだ
It's starting all over again.
shout my song!
本気だって言わなくってきっと伝わるよ
Even without saying we mean it, it's bound to get across.
何度でも熱くなれ自由に慣れ
No matter when, be passionate, be free.
believe
( believe )
again
( again )
また始まるんだ
It's starting all over again.
( yeah )
yeah
yeah!!
( yeah )
yeah
そう遊びじゃないよ let's go
Yes, it's not just play, let's go.
折れた絆は割れないよ let's go
Our broken bonds will never break, let's go.
3, 2, 1, go!
three, two, one, go!
we can go, we can go
ah もっと信じて
ah, believe more
we can fly, we can fly
so どんな夢も
so any dream
we can go, we can go
ah もっと信じて
ah, believe more
we can fly, we can fly
so きっと叶う yeah!
so it will surely come true, yeah!
はい！ということで！
Hai! So that means...
次の曲で最後のお祭りだー！
the next song is the festival's ending!
イェーイ！イェーイ！うおー！
Yay, yay, yay! Woo!
ふー…
Phew...
やばい、これ！
That's intense!
めちゃめちゃ激しくてきっと伝わるよ！
It's super intense, it'll definitely get through!
あ、間違っちゃった、実は私…
Wait, I messed up, actually me...
あ、祭りも…
The festival too—
もっと激しいようにしなきゃ！
We had to make it more intense!
激しいようにしなきゃって思ったんだけどさ。
ということでね、今日これアイドル衣装で
So today, this is Idols' Fashion—
そうなんです。
That's right.
そう、一緒に！
So together,
で、こんなお揃いの髪飾りもつけてね！
and wearing these matching hair accessories...
可愛い！
So cute!
一緒に踊らせていただきました！
We were able to dance together!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、ということでね、歌ったのはSaint Snowの「Believe again」でしたー！
And the song was Saint Snow's "Believe again"!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
すいちゃんとも本当に…
Suu-chan and I really—
すっごいダンスの練習を…
had really intense dance practice.
いや、本当に！しました！
Yeah, really!
そう、はじめも全然できなくて！
Right, at first I couldn't do it at all!
遠い遠いやんの、みたいなん。
So far away!
ここここここ！あ、こう、こうやって！
Where, where, where? Ah, like this!
移動忘れた！ダンス！
I forgot the choreography!
そうそうそう、このへんとかやりながらさ。
Right around here...
間違ったりとかあったんだけど。
There were mistakes, but...
あ、私、大丈夫、ちゃんとできた？
Wait, did I actually do okay?
めちゃめちゃよかった！さすが！
It was super good! As expected.
よかったー。安心しました。実は、私…
I'm relieved. Actually...
実は、途中で完全にダンス忘れて。
I messed up half of it!
そうなの？
Is that so?
そう、半分以上ね。焦ったよね。
Yeah, for more than half!
はあー！さー、なんか、踊りちょっと…
Haha, phew.
帰ってきた、返ってきたのここ怖いんだけど。
I'm grateful to come back here, though I'm a bit scared.
でも、なんか、あの、踊りは本当に、なんかすっごい総会…
But you know, the dance really felt like a finale,
なんか本当に、うん、やりきったっていう気持ちが…
like we really gave it our all.
でかい！
It's huge.
いや、本当に。
Yeah, really.
いや、ありがとうございました！
Yeah, thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
まつりちゃんね、あの、まつりちゃんの、あれ、誕生日だっけ？
Matsuri-chan, right? Matsuri-chan's—
そう、誕生日ね。だっけ？うんだっけ？うん。
Yeah, around then.
その時にあの指いただきましたて。
At that time, you received that finger.
その時はね、一緒に歌って踊りたいっていう…
So at that time, you wanted us to sing and dance together.
そう、気持ちがあったので、今日ここでかなえられて嬉しかった！
That feeling was there, so being able to fulfill it here today makes me so happy!
ありがとうー！嬉しい！
Thank you so much!
よかったー。
I'm so glad.
次は祭りのね、チャンネルでもね、一緒に歌って踊りたい！
Next time, I want to sing and dance together on Matsuri's channel too!
そうしましょう！歌って踊りたい！あ…
Let's do that! Singing and dancing together—
だって、我々は！アイドルだからー！
Wait, because we're idols!
いや、アイドルではない。そういう意味のアイドルではない、こん…
Well, we're not quite that kind of idol, maybe?
こういうのがしつこく…そう、今日出てこなかった。
Stuff like that keeps popping out, but it didn't come out today.
ああ、おもしろ。
Haha, that's funny.
でもすいちゃん、ありがとう！
Suu-chan, thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで、え…
And so, um...
実は、まだゲストがいるんです。
Actually, we still have a guest!
では、次の曲いきましょう！
Then let's sing the next song!
ねぇ、いこう！
Let's go!
見上げれば青空
If you look up, there is a blue sky...
作詞：坂井季乃 / 作曲・編曲：高橋諒 (Void (Chords))
[Lyrics: Natsuiro Matsuri / Music & Arrangement: Takahashi Void (Chords)]
その向こうに行きたいの
I want to go to the other side.
焦がれれば 焦がれるほど 遠く
The more I yearn for it, the further away it gets...
翼ならあるのに
Even though I have wings,
開き方忘れてしまった 風に乗る
I've forgotten how to open them to ride the wind.
イメージさえも 今ではもう
Even the image of it is now gone...
また一つひらりと落ちた その羽を
Another feather fluttered down...
あなたは拾い上げ 臆病な私を誘うように
...and you picked it up, as if inviting my cowardly self.
宙に投げたんだ
You tossed it into the sky.
ゆっくりと手をひらいて 息を吸って待つように
Slowly open your hand, like waiting while taking a breath...
からだが 細胞が 応えているよと あなたが言うから
Because you tell me that my body and cells are responding...
空を見上げ あの子は 何よりも綺麗に見えた そのせいで
When I looked up at the sky, that child looked more beautiful than anything else...
誰も届かないところへ……
To a place where no one can reach...
大人になり ひらりとまた 羽根が今 あの子に重なった
Growing up, feathers once again overlapped with that child,
どこまでも自由に飛べるように 歌を添えるよ
so that they could fly freely anywhere, I add a song.
ゆっくりと手をひらいて 息を吸って待つように
Slowly open your hand, like waiting while taking a breath...
からだが 細胞が 応えているよと あなたが言うから
Because you tell me that my body and cells are responding...
かごを飛び出して 自由を手にした
I flew out of the cage and took freedom into my hands.
鳥が奏でる音に 私はたどって 歌う
Following the sound of the birds playing, I sing,
どこまでも高く響いて
echoing high up into the endless sky.
息をしている
I'm breathing,
君は生きている
so you're alive.
当然のこと 誰も疑わないの
It's so obvious, no one doubts it.
息をしている ように見えている
It looks like I'm breathing.
背の裏側 私にとっての何か
What does the reverse side mean to me?
鼓動が ドクドク している
My heart is beating wildly.
叩かれても 腐らずに
Even if struck down, without rotting,
ここで歌うよ ボタン一つのいのち
I'll sing right here, a life of a single button.
最後まで 私のこと 覚えていてくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I'm about to fade away, understand it, please understand!
本当のとこなの？ 恋人同士なんでしょ？
Is that really true? We're lovers, right?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなってしまうの
If you forget, I'll end up disappearing.
命のような夢を見ているよ またね、バイバイ。
I'm dreaming a dream like life. See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive.
自己証明を 欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ
Desiring, desperately desiring proof of existence.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the sound stops and everything stands still,
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll smile at someone like me.
鼓動が ドクドク している
My heart is beating wildly.
嫌われても 腐らずに ここで歌うよ
Even if I'm disliked, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
気分次第のいのち 命のような夢を見てるよ
A life on a whim, dreaming a dream like life.
最後まで 私のこと 届けてくれるの？
Will you convey my feelings until the very end?
冷めてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよ ねぇ
I'm about to grow cold, understand it, please understand!
声が超えるんだよ 塩辛い涙が出ちゃうほど
My voice echoes across, to the point of salty tears.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなってしまうの
If you forget, I'll end up disappearing.
命のような夢を見ているよ またね、バイバイ。
I'm dreaming a dream like life. See you later, bye-bye.
塞ぎ込んだあの日を 軽く捻じらないで やめて
Don't lightly twist that gloomy day, stop it.
それが生きる過程になるから だから
Because that becomes part of the process of living, so...
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's okay, I will keep on singing forever.
最後まで 私は 生きているか わからないけど
I don't know if I'll stay alive until the very end, but
君がくれた言葉は 確かに 残ってる
the words you gave me definitely remain.
最後まで 私を 覚えていなくてもいいから
You don't even have to remember me until the end.
いつか尽きてしまうだろう わからない わからないよ ねぇ
It will run out someday, I don't know, I don't know, hey...
命のような夢を見ているよ またね、バイバイ。
I'm dreaming a dream like life. See you later, bye-bye.
はい、ということで、ありがとうございましたー！
Well, thank you very much!
はい、最後のゲストはそらちゃんとあずきちちゃんでしたー！
Yes, our final guests were Sora-chan and Azukichi!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you!
Thank you very much!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations!
もうね、本当、そらちゃんとは、えっと、デジタルの、えっと...
Well really, with Sora-chan, um, digitally, um...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫？ 大丈夫？ 大丈夫？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
出会いまして、あずきちとは命を、デジタルの時に歌わせていただいて...
We met, and I had the chance to sing with Azukichi when we did the digital...
で、もうそらちゃんとも、なんかすごい、なんか考え深いし、あずきちとも今ここに立ってるのはすごい考え深いし
And with Sora-chan too, it's so profound, and standing here right now with Azukichi is also so profound.
あのね、本当に、あのいのちって言う曲はですね、私が、あの、インディーズのミュージカルに入って、あの...
You know, truly, that song called 'Inochi' is a song where, when I joined indie music, um...
初めての、なんか、出させて頂いたライブ...ね、ね、あの、歌わせていただいたんですけど、その時も...
It was my very first live performance that I was allowed to be in... right, right, um, I got to sing it, and even back then...
泣いて、歌えなく、ライブを間違って、本当に、あの...
I was crying so much I couldn't sing, messed up the live, and really, um...
すいません、でしで、ずびー、ずびー、ねえ、本当にもう...
I'm sorry, it was, sniff, sniff, you know, really...
もうなんか、本当に、なんか、なんだろう、すごい、2人で一緒に歌えてよかったなって、本当に思います。
I really feel, like, how wonderful it was to be able to sing together with the two of them.
ありがとうございます！本当におめでとう！
Thank you so much! Congratulations!
いや、本当にあのスイちゃんのほうから今回ね、お誘いいただいて、もう本当にスイちゃんと会うのも、もうね本当に久しぶりで、もう1年以上ぶりぐらいに、やっとね一緒にこうやって...
Well, really, Suisei-chan invited me this time, and it's been so long since I last saw Suisei-chan—probably over a year—and we were finally able to...
こうやってステージに立つことができて、本当に嬉しい。本当に素敵な時間でした。スイちゃんありがとう！
stand on stage together like this. I'm so happy. It was truly a wonderful time. Thank you, Sui-chan!
ありがとうございます！あのなんか、何かつなが違っていたら、多分数私はまだ、どこかで、あずきちゃ、あずきちちゃんと一緒にどっかのステージで一緒に歌ってたかもしれないし...
Thank you so much! You know, if things had been slightly different, maybe I'd still somewhere be singing on stage with Azukichi...
で、も今はね、私はもうインディーズミュージックを抜けて、ソロライブとして、まね、あの、歌わせていただいているので、なんかこういう機会にね、こういう時に歌えて本当に嬉しかったです。
But now, you know, I've left indie music and am singing as a solo live artist, so being able to sing on an occasion like this, at a time like this, made me so happy.
ありがとうございます！そらちゃん持ってる！
Thank you so much! Sora-chan is holding it!
これ後歌えるか私！スイちゃん可愛いよ、今日も可愛いよ！
Can I even sing after this?! Sui-chan is so cute, you're cute today too!
ありがとうございます！いや本当にお二人ともありがとうございました！おめでとう！
Thank you so much! Well, truly, thank you both! Congratulations!
はい、じゃあお二人ともありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！おめでとう！
Yes, well, thank you both very much! Thank you! Congratulations!
頑張ります！はい！
I'll do my best! Yes!
ということで、いやー、やっちまったよ！感極まってしまった本当に。あー、まね、これもあの生の醍醐味ということで...
And so, man, I really messed up! I got so emotional. Ah, well, that's the true thrill of live performances...
ということで、これから、えっと、最後の歌を歌うんですけれども、その前に皆さんちょっと気になってることがあると思うんですけど
So, from now on, um, I'll be singing the final song, but before that, I think there's something everyone is wondering about...
あの、グッズ！グッズですよ！グッズ！
Um, merchandise! It's merchandise! Merchandise!
ちょっと出ますかね？どどん！
Can it be shown? Ta-da!
あ、でました！星街すいせい50万人記念ライブの記念グッズが販売されます！
Ah, it's out! Commemorative merchandise for Hoshimachi Suisei's 500k subscriber live will be available!
え、手島nari先生B2タペストリー、星街すいせい今日もかわいいアクリルスタンドの、えこちら再販、
Um, Hande Nari-sensei B2 Tapestry, Hoshimachi Suisei 'So Cute Today Too' Acrylic Stand (re-sale),
星街すいせい描き下ろしフェイスタオル、星街すいせい描き下ろしTシャツがですね、
Hoshimachi Suisei illustrated face towel, and Hoshimachi Suisei illustrated T-shirt,
え、この後配信終わりの10時から、え、配信販売が、販売じゃなくて、あの開始されますので、ぜひチェックしてください！
um, starting at 10 PM right after this stream ends, sales will begin—well, not sales, but will open, so please check it out!
次の画像行こかな？
Shall we go to the next image?
お、こちら見て！ねえ見てこの、Tシャツ、Tシャツ！Tシャツさ、よくない？ちょっとめっちゃおしゃれなんだよね、おしゃれ、おしゃれ！
Oh, look at this! Hey, look at this T-shirt, T-shirt! Isn't this T-shirt great? It's super stylish, stylish, stylish!
ね、あの、Tシャツ、あこれTシャツアップにできますか？できる、できる。ちょっともうちょっとさ、デザインを見せたいんだわ、めちゃめちゃ
Hey, um, T-shirt, oh can we zoom in on the T-shirt? We can, we can. Let's show the design a bit more, really—
できるかな？星街すいせい描き下ろしフェイスタオル、星街すいせい描き下ろしTシャツですね、
Can we do it? Hoshimachi Suisei illustrated face towel, Hoshimachi Suisei illustrated T-shirt,
私が、あ、ありがとうございます！手描きさせていただきました！すごくない？おしゃれでしょ？おしゃれでしょ？
I—ah, thank you so much! I drew it by hand! Isn't it amazing? Isn't it stylish? Isn't it stylish?
あ、そう、忘れてたんですけど、あの、言うの、今回のですね、あの、ライブのタイトルが、Start & Inja Screen... となっております。
Ah right, I forgot to mention, um, the title of this live stream is 'Start & In the Screen'... wait.
このね、あの、Eのところが3つ連なって、音符みたいになってるのこれかっこいいでしょ？これをもう一度ついたとき私、あ天才だなってみんなに...
You see, um, where the three 'E's line up like music notes, isn't that cool? When I realized that, I thought, 'Ah, I'm a genius' to everyone...
ありがとう！みんなありがとう、ぜひぜひ買って下さい！えっとこの後10時から販売開始です。
Thank you! Thank you everyone, please, please buy it! Um, sales start at 10 PM right after this.
あとは、えっと、星街すいせい50万人記念ライブ、あれ？
And also, um, Hoshimachi Suisei 500k subscriber live, huh?
ちょっと！あ、もしかしてももう10時になってる？あ、じゃあもう開始してますわ！じゃあもう開始してますわ！あ、ぜひ買って下さい！
Wait! Ah, could it already be 10 PM? Ah, then it's already started! Then it's already started! Ah, please buy it!
あと、あの星街すいせい50万人記念ライブのハッシュタグをつけて、ぜひぜひたくさんツイートしてくださいね！ありがとうございます！
Also, please use the hashtag for Hoshimachi Suisei's 500k subscriber live and tweet lots of things! Thank you so much!
はい、では、そんなこんなで...
Well then, with that all said...
最後の曲をお聴きいただきたいと思います。
I'd like you to listen to the final song.
ええ、50万人に来るまで、本当にあの簡単な道では
Um, until reaching 500,000 subscribers, really, it wasn't an easy path,
なかったんですけれども、こうして みんなの前でこんな素敵なライブをやらせていただける、
but being able to perform such a wonderful live stream in front of everyone like this,
そんな人間に慣れて、そんなホロドルになれて 本当によかった。
becoming such a person, becoming such a holodol, I'm really glad.
VTuberを続けてて本当に良かったなと思います。
I think it was truly great that I continued being a VTuber.
本当にありがとうございます。これからもどうぞ、星街すいせいの応援をよろしくお願いいたします。
Thank you very much. From now on as well, please continue to support Hoshimachi Suisei.
では、最後の曲、聴いてください。ダイヤモンド・クレバス。
Now then, please listen to the final song: Diamond Crevasse.
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was in love with God,
こんな別れがくるとは思っていなかったよ
I didn't think that such a parting would come.
もう二度と触れられないのなら
If I couldn't ever touch you again,
せめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
Then I'd want you to embrace me again for the last time at least.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 何度だって
Goodbye, goodbye, over and over again
自分に 無上に 言い聞かせて
I tell myself as best as I can
手を振るのは 優しさだよね?
That waving my hand is kindness, right?
今強さが欲しい
Now, I want strength
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I encountered you; the star shined and I was born
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Indeed if I love, indeed if there's I
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に浸る 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりも
I won't forget your warmth
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
And your kindness, and both hands that embraced everything.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 愛しい人
Goodbye, goodbye, my beloved person
貴方が いたから 歩いてこれた
Because you were here, I was able to walk up to now
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね?
I wasn't alone, right?
今答えが欲しい
Now, I want an answer
燃える様な流星 捕まえて 火を灯して
Catch the burning shooting star and light a fire
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love, I want to be loved
冷えたカラダひとつで 世界は どうなるの?
With just a cold body, what will happen to the world?
張り続けてた 虚勢が溶けていく long for...
My sustained bravado melts away, long for...
どうしてなの? 涙溢れて 止められない
Why? Tears overflow and cannot be stopped
貴方に出会い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
I encountered you; the star shined and I was born
愛せばこそ iがあればこそ
Indeed if I love, indeed if there's I
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
Waiting for a hopeless miracle, what will become of me?
涙に浸る 惑星の瞬きは gone...
The twinkle of planets stained with tears is gone...
もし生まれ変わって また巡り会えるなら
If I am reborn and we can meet again
その時もきっとなんとか見つけ出してもう二度と離さないで
At that time, please definitely find me, don't ever let go of me again...
あなたに出逢い スター輝いて アタシが生まれて
I met you, the stars sparkled, and I was born.
愛すればこそ
Because we loved each other,
愛し合えばこそ
Because we shared our love,
希望のない奇跡を待ってどうなるの?
What's the point of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に滲む 惑星の瞬きは
Through my tear-filled vision, the planet's twinkle
gone…
is gone...
星生まれ変わって また巡り逢えるなら
If we are reincarnated and can meet again someday,
その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
please find me when that time comes.
もう二度と離さないで つかまえてて
Make sure you never let go again.
ひとりじゃないと
Whisper to me
ささやいて 欲しいplanet…
that I'm not alone, planet...
チャンネル登録者 50万人記念 3rd Youtube Live
500k Subscribers Milestone: 3rd YouTube Live